yatango.com.au 2014-03-30

# Yatango Privacy Policy | Yatango Mobile

  1. Introduction
  2. How will we collect information?
  3. What information will Yatango Mobile collect?
  4. How do we use this Information?
  5. Disclosure of Information
  6. Retention of Information
  7. Assessing your Information
  8. Security and Protection
  9. Avoiding Spam
  10. Changes to this Privacy Policy
  11. Contact Us

### 1\. Introduction

#### 1.1 This privacy policy will explain

  * How we collect information about our members.
  * The information that we require.
  * What your personal information may be used for.
  * How you can access and update your information profile.

#### 1.2 Principles

Yatango Mobile is bound by the National Privacy Principles under the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth). As a supplier of telecommunications services, we have certain obligations under different laws, regulations and industry codes, including the Telecommunications Act 1997.

#### 1.3 Why do we collect this Information

All phone networks require this information for many reasons, this may be due to a legal obligation or because we simply wish to have a good relationship between our staff and members. Yatango Mobile will collect this information electronically when you order your SIM card. It may be thought of as slightly intrusive and a bit over the top, though it is all relevant information which we need from all new members. This document will explain how all of your personal information will be kept safe and that you should have no concerns when supplying us with what we need.

#### 1.4 Our Obligation

It is our obligation to fulfil what is required by the law; this includes assisting with legal proceedings, crimes, fraud, protection, detection and prosecution.

#### 1.5 Our Members

We want to get to know our members, so having your contact details means you can give us your opinion any time and we are able to provide you with useful and helpful information. The main reason we collect this personal information is to provide you with our service, it means you can be identified as an individual/valued Yatango Mobile member.

#### 1.6 Examples of what your information may be used for

  * Business planning and development
  * Billing
  * Informing you about any problems we may come across
  * Letting you know about our services and how we can help you with your phone usage
  * Providing you with the chance to share your opinions
  * Providing you with promotional messages/offers (which you can request to avoid)
  * Receiving advice (legal or financial)
  * Complying to your customer obligations
  * To assist with fraud prevention agencies

#### Notifications

In most cases, you will be notified before we collect any personal information, you WILL have access to any personal information we own, and must let Yatango Mobile know if any changes need to be made to our records. In some situations we may be unable to advise you of any collected information, we promise to let you know as soon as possible after the collection.

Please Note: Any sensitive information will not be collected without the consent of a Yatango Mobile Member.

Sensitive information will NOT be used for marketing purposes – this information will only be used in circumstances which may be a threat to someone’s safety and if we are required to do so by a relevant authority (for investigation).

### 2\. How will we collect information?

We will collect personal information in many different ways which are outlined below:  
Please Note: most information is collected through you, when you join the Yatango Mobile service.

  * When you purchase your SIM card you will be asked to fill out personal details.
  * When you register as a Yatango Mobile member.
  * When you use any of our products or services.
  * When you contact us with queries or comments.
  * When you enter in any competitions or promotions.
  * When you take part in market research.
  * If you cancel your SIM.
  * Business directories and other public sources.

### 3\. What sort of information will Yatango Mobile Collect?

  * Name
  * Address
  * Date of Birth
  * Email Address
  * Credit/Debit Card details
  * Other financial Details
  * Government identification numbers (drivers licence or passport number)
  * Details from other services (telephone calls made and received and other methods of communication which you may use)

Reassurance:  
All employees will treat personal information with they respect a member expects, and we will carry out all legal obligations in this area.

All information will be stored safely and can be accessed easily by the Yatango Mobile staff.

### 4\. How do we use this Information?

The reason why we collect this personal information is to:

  * Provide you with access to different parts of our site
  * Contact you
  * Inform you of any service related issues
  * We can reduce the risk of crime and fraud by checking identities
  * Investigate complaints made by customers
  * Personalise our SIM's to meet your needs and expectations
  * Analyse the market and produce reports
  * Market our services to you
  * Provide you with information
  * Debt tracing, debt recovery, credit management and crime, fraud and money detection and prevention.
  * Store your data usage and service usage, to ensure that you can see exactly what you are paying for and if it is right for you.
  * We can use information such as your call time or browsing time to provide information for offers, promotions or commercial communications.

### 5\. Disclosure of information

#### 5.1. Your information may be used for

  * For the purpose of Billing and debt-recovery service providers.
  * For the use of Information technology suppliers.
  * To help in Social Media Management.
  * For financial reasons - Macquarie Bank (as explained below)
  * By a relevant public authority or law enforcement agency.
  * In emergencies when personal safety may be at risk.
  * Where our service is moderated.
  * In response to a complaint which breaches our terms and conditions.
  * If there is a change of the ownership of Yatango Mobile.
  * If any information you have provided is false.
  * In response to a valid, legally compliant request by some authority.

#### 5.2. Macquarie Bank

Some personal information may be used by Macquarie Bank, as Yatango Mobile is supplied with merchant facilities by Macquarie Bank. This enables us to complete credit and debit card transactions from our members. This is in regards to payment of your bills. Macquarie Bank may need access to some of your personal information, in some cases Yatango Mobile will not have access to parts of your information as it will be collected directly by Macquarie Bank – some of this information may be necessary by laws and regulations. This is important in fulfilling legal obligations such as Anti- Money Laundering and Counter-Terrorism.

You may access your personal information by contacting the Macquarie Bank customer service team on 1800 806 310

Please Note: If any information supplied to Macquarie is incorrect, transactions may not be possible.

### 6\. Retention of Information

We will keep your information for as long as we need it, we should have access to your information more than 6 months but less than 2 years, this is to ensure that the information is available for investigation and prosecution of serious crimes.

### 7 Assessing your Information

#### 7.1 Registered Members

If you are a registered member with Yatango Mobile, you will have access to some of your information through your profile when you log in to your homepage. Yatango Mobile will try to keep all personal information it collects uses and retains about you accurate and up-to-date.

If there are any errors throughout your information, for example a change of address, please let us know so that we can keep all information on our records up to date.

#### 7.2 Your Rights

You have the right to ‘opt-out’ of certain information when you are a member with Yatango Mobile, for example community activity messages. If you wish to bar these messages coming to your phone you can turn off notifications via your ‘Account Settings’.

#### 7.3 The Law

You will receive any information which must be sent out by law.

#### 7.4 Third Parties

We will not give your information to third parties unless you agree for us to do so. No harm can come to your identity by doing so, though it is of course completely your decision. There are certain services which you will not receive if you fail to provide all of your personal information.

### 8\. Security and Protection

#### 8.1. Communication

All members should be aware that communications over the internet are not always secure unless they are encrypted. Yatango cannot take responsibility for any unauthorised access or missing information as it is beyond our control.

#### 8.2. Members under 16

A parent/guardian must give a child under 16 permission to provide any personal information to Yatango Mobile. No personal information should be disclosed without such consent. Yatango Mobile accepts no responsibility for how consent is obtained.

#### 8.3. Cookies

This is a piece of information, just like a tag which is created between websites which identifies your mobile phone or PC whenever you visit the website. Yatango can create cookies when you visit our site, these can be used to:

  * Limit the amount of advertisements and announcements on the Yatango site
  * Identify defaults to customise your homepage
  * Keep track of specific services you use
  * If referred to our portal you can track where you are
  * Provide you with information to help you
  * Make our email announcements more relevant to you by using your personal information.

### 9\. Avoiding Spam

Watch who you give your email address to – try to avoid giving your email address on websites, chat rooms or to other companies.

  * Limit the amount of advertisements and announcements on the Yatango site
  * Identify defaults to customise your homepage
  * Keep track of specific services you use
  * If referred to our portal you can track where you are
  * Provide you with information to help you
  * Make our email announcements more relevant to you by using your personal information.

### 10\. Changes to this Privacy Policy

This policy is kept under constant review and any changes may occur at any time throughout the year. We would advise that you please keep an eye out for any adjustments.

### 11\. Contact Us

Have a question?  
Please visit our HELP page for all the help and support you need for all things Yatango.
